<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<seiscomp>
	<plugin name="FilterPicker">
		<extends>global</extends>
		<description>
		The FilterPicker plugin implements a robust, broadband picker for real-time
		seismic monitoring based on the FilterPicker algorithm by Lomax et al. (2012).
		It operates on multiple frequency bands using characteristic functions to detect
		and pick seismic phases. The algorithm is particularly well suited for
		earthquake early warning applications and real-time seismic monitoring.
		Reference: Lomax, A., Satriano, C., &amp; Vassallo, M. (2012). Automatic picker
		developments and optimization: FilterPicker - a robust, broadband picker for
		real-time seismic monitoring and earthquake early-warning. Seismological
		Research Letters, 83(3), 531-540.
		</description>
	</plugin>
	<binding name="FilterPicker" module="global">
		<configuration>
			<group name="picker">
				<group name="FilterPicker">
					<description>
					FilterPicker P-phase picking parameters. This picker implements
					a multi-band approach with characteristic function computation
					for robust broadband phase detection.
					</description>
					<parameter name="numBands" type="int" default="5">
						<description>
						Number of frequency bands for the filter bank. More bands
						provide better frequency coverage but increase computational
						cost. Recommended range: 4-8 bands.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="minFreq" type="double" default="0.5" unit="Hz">
						<description>
						Minimum frequency of the filter bank in Hz. The bands are
						logarithmically spaced between minFreq and maxFreq.
						Typical: 0.5 Hz for P-phase (broadband).
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="maxFreq" type="double" default="20.0" unit="Hz">
						<description>
						Maximum frequency of the filter bank in Hz. The bands are
						logarithmically spaced between minFreq and maxFreq.
						Automatically limited to 95% of Nyquist. Typical: 20 Hz.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="windowSize" type="int" default="2" unit="s">
						<description>
						Integration window size in seconds. The characteristic
						function is integrated over this window to enhance detection.
						Fast response: 1s, Default: 2s, Noisy: 3-5s.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="threshold" type="double" default="2.0">
						<description>
						Detection threshold for the characteristic function ratio.
						Lower values increase sensitivity but may produce more
						false picks. Sensitive: 1.5-2.0, Default: 2.0, Conservative: 2.5-3.5.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="thresholdOff" type="double" default="1.5">
						<description>
						Threshold for resetting the detector after a pick. The
						detector will reset when the characteristic function falls
						below this value.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="adaptiveThreshold" type="boolean" default="true">
						<description>
						Enable adaptive thresholding based on noise level. When
						enabled, the detection threshold is automatically scaled based
						on the background noise level. Recommended for most installations.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="noiseBegin" type="double" default="-10.0" unit="s">
						<description>
						Start of noise window relative to trigger time in seconds.
						This window is used to compute noise statistics for SNR
						calculation and pick uncertainty estimation.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="signalBegin" type="double" default="-5.0" unit="s">
						<description>
						Start of signal window relative to trigger time in seconds.
						The pick search begins at this time relative to trigger.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="signalEnd" type="double" default="20.0" unit="s">
						<description>
						End of signal window relative to trigger time in seconds.
						The pick search ends at this time.
						</description>
					</parameter>
					<parameter name="minSNR" type="double" default="2.0">
						<description>
						Minimum signal-to-noise ratio required for a valid pick.
						Picks with SNR below this threshold are rejected.
						Accept more: 1.5-2.0, Default: 2.0, High quality: 3.0-5.0.
						</description>
					</parameter>
				</group>
			</group>
		</configuration>
	</binding>
</seiscomp>
